Rithik Banerjee

.Net Developer

Passionate software developer with around one year of experience in .Net framework, that includes understanding system requirements, designing architecture, development, testing, updating and support of commercial application. Extensive knowledge in object oriented programming, client side web development, database management and version control.

- banerjee13rithik@gmail.com
- Kidwai Nagar, Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh, India
- in linkedin.com/in/RithikBanerjee
- github.com/RithikBanerjee

- (+91) 990 347 1021
- rithikbanerjee.github.io/Responsive-Resume
- live:banerjee13rithik
 - tackoverflow.com/users/13430233

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Opticodes Technologies

07/2019 - Present

Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh

Full Time Web Developer responsible for planing architecture, coding, versioning and maintaining a GST portal and a GSP portal.

- Developed custom, general use modules and components namely, Query Creator, Dapper Method Store, Request Handler, Validation Engine, etc.
- Built a general purpose class library to import data in bulk from excel sheet to database irrespective of its template and header.
- Created E-invoice and E-way bill generating portal using NIC APIS.
- Researched and evaluted technologies that created value for the company.

iOS Developer

TenPi Technologies 🗷

05/2017 - 07/2017

Kolkata, West Bengal

Intern iOS Developer responsible for building a iOS app using Xcode 7.3.1 which would finds nearby bluetooth devices.

- Built a beacon iOS application on Xcode using Bluetooth 4.0.
- Responsible for the version maintenance of the iOS application.
- Designed the UI/UX for the iOS application using Adobe Illustrator.
- Integrated cloud based database for registered beacon devices in the iOS application.

TECHNICAL SKILLS



PROJECTS

Python

Aleph (04/2020 - 05/2020) 🗹

Django

It is a python web application based on Django framework.

OpenCV

Excel Data Importer (01/2020 – 03/2020)

- Class library used to import excel data to any data type.

GSP SDK (11/2019 – 02/2020) 🗹

 Class library used as software development tool for building gst-based softwares.

Iris Detector (09/2018 – 04/2019)

 Detects and segments out the iris region from a non ideal eye images using multiple image processing techniques.

HOBBIES

Competitive Coding 🗹

Content Writing 🛂

EDUCATION

B. Tech in Computer Science

Jalpaiguri Government Engineering College ♂

2015 – 2019 West Bengal

LANGUAGES

English
Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency